http://subscene.com/u/659433 Improved by: @Ivandrofly
https://github.com/KoSubs/Silicon-Valley--2014-
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR) - Holy shit.
이런...
- Uh... - What the fuck is that?
- 어... - 저 좃같은 건 뭐야?
Uh, that is Jared Dunn.
어, '재레드 던'이네.
He works for Gavin Belson.
개빈 벨슨 밑에서 일하는 놈이야.
Hey. Sorry if I scared you.
안녕. 놀라게 했으면 미안해.
I know I have somewhat ghost-like features.
내가 좀 유령처럼 구는 구석이 있어.
My Uncle used to say,
삼촌의 평가로는 갓 굶어죽은 사람같다고 하더라고.
It's... yeah. I can see it.
그게... 그런 것 같기도 하네.
I heard you were having a launch party.
창업 기념 회식한다고 들었어.
- Yeah. - Am I early?
- 맞아. - 네가 너무 일찍 왔나??
No.
아니야.
Well then, a gift of congratulations.
음... 그러면 이건 축하 선물이야.
Now, if Gavin sent you here,
그게, 개빈이 보내서 온거면,
you should know that I've turned him down.
내가 그 제안을 거절했다는 걸 알아야 할 것 같네.
I'm going with Peter Gregory.
피터 그레고리의 제안을 받아들이기로 했거든.
I'm actually picking up my check tomorrow.
내일 돈 받으로갈 예정이야.
So I've made my decision.
그렇게 하기로 했어.
That's not why I'm here. It's just... (SIGHS)
그것 때문에 온게 아니야. 그게...
Watching you say no to ten million dollars to build your own thing,
100억원을 거절하려는 것을 보니까
there's just something very exciting about that.
나도 뭔가 끌어오르는게 있더라고
Whoa. Whoa, whoa! What is he doing here?
이런. 이런, 이런! 쟤 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
Hey, this is a private party, buddy. I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
이봐, 이 파티는 우리끼리 할 거라고, 친구. 나가주셔야 겠어.
- Oh, I didn't mean to... - You know, in the state of California
- 어, 전 그게 아니라... - 캘리포니아에서는 허락없이 집에 들어오면
you can kill a man for entering your house without permission.
죽여버려도 되는 것 알고 있지?
Ok. I understand. Uh, thank you.
넵. 무슨 말씀이신지 알겠습니다.
Richard, I just wanna say, I really respect what you're doing here.
리차드, 내가 하고 싶은 말은, 네 선택에 대해 정말 존중하고 있어.
And if you could ever use someone with my business development skill set,
그리고 혹시 비즈니스용 개발 능력을 필요하다면,
I would love to be a part of this.
나도 끼고 싶어.
The fuck you will be.
잘도 그렇게 되겠지.
We'll call you when we want pleated khakis.
주름진 카키 바지가 필요하면 연락하도록 하지.
You know this is a fucking domestic?
이거 졸라 싸구려 아냐?
Why... why were you so mean to him?
던한테 왜 그렇게 군거예요?
He wasn't spying on us. He just said he likes us.
염탐짓하러 온게 아니예요. 우리를 맘에 들어한다고요.
- He wants to join the company. - Of course he does, Richard.
- 우리 회사에 들어올려고 한다고요. - 당연히 그렇겠지. 이봐.
Let me explain something to you.
뭐 좀 가르쳐줄게 있어.
Your whole life you've been an ugly chick
넌 여태까지 미운오리 새끼였어.
but now suddenly you're a hot chick,
그러다가 갑자기 크고 예쁜 가슴가진 여자애처럼 섹시해진 거라고.
So guys like that are gonna keep coming around.
그래서 아까 그놈 같은 늑대 새끼가 네 주변을 어슬렁 거리는 거라고.
Don't be a slut, Richard.
그런 놈들한테 쉽게 다리를 벌리면 안되.
- I don't... - (DOORBELL RINGS)
나, 난...
Now speaking of such things,
여자 얘기가 나온 김에...
Dinesh, change the lighting to something erotic
디네시, 조명 좀 에로틱하게 바꿔봐.
because it's about to get pretty fucking erotic in here.
좃나게 야한 걸 준비해 놨으니까.
License to kill-9. IB action-dot-erotica.
kill-9 허가. IB 액션.에로키타.
Wha... what... What's going on?
이.. 이...이게 뭐야??
- What's happening? - Gentlemen, I present to you...
- 뭘 준비했다는 거죠? - 신사여러분, 모카치노를...
Mochacino.
소개합니다.
Not this guy.
이 사람이 아니고....
She's my gift to you.
내가 준비한 선물이야.
You wanna smoke weed?
대마초 줄까?
Hey.
이봐요.
Can somebody play something with a beat, please?
음악 좀 뛰어 줄래요?
I'll go make a playlist.
내가 음악을 준비할께.
Yeah. I actually have some... some water, uh, cooking, I think.
어. 그게... 물이나, 음, 음식이 좀 있을텐데...
Yeah, I don't pay for it. So...
음, 난 그게 좀 별로라...
Barking up the wrong tree here.
엉뚱한 사람한테 말 걸었네.
God, I hate Palo Alto.
젠장, 짜증나는 팔로 알토.
Hello again.
또 뵙네요.
You know, I don't actually have a ton of dance music
그게, 댄스 음악이 별로 없더라고요.
but I turned the bass way up.
그래서 베이스를 좀 쎄게 올렸어요.
Baby...
자기...
you're getting a private show.
일대일 서비스를 해줄께요.
What the fuck?
이 뭐...
Ok. There's the butt time.
엉덩이 타임이네...
Hey, should we have left him in there by himself?
쟤만 혼자 냅둬도 되는걸까?
I mean, should we go back in there?
그러니까, 우리도 저리로 가야하는 것 아냐?
No interest. I entice the flesh, I don't pay for it.
관심없어. 여자 꼬셔서 노는 건 좋지만, 돈 주고 하는 건 싫어.
Plus, Tara's coming into town in a couple weeks.
거기에, 몇 주만 있으면 타라가 돌아오거든.
I'm saving up all my humors for her.
타라를 위해서 내 에너지를 모아둬야해.
You know what I mean?
뭔 말인지 알지?
- What's your excuse? - I didn't even shake
- 넌 왜 도망쳤는데? - 난 17살때까지만 해도
a woman's hand until I was 17-years-old.
여자랑 악수도 해본 적 없는 몸이야.
The idea of getting an erection around men I live and work with,
같이 일하면서 같이 사는 사내 새끼들이랑 같이 있으면서 빨딱 세운다는건
it's just not something I can handle.
내가 감당할 수 있는 일이 아니야.
The idea that I have a boner and you have a boner
전부 다 같이 앉아 있아서 나도, 너도, 얘도 다 꼴려 있다고 생각하면...
I wonder if he's ok in there.
쟤는 괜찮은지 모르겠네.
So what do you guys do here?
그래서 당신들이 하는 일이 뭐예요?
Oh, we're mostly working on a lossless compression algorithm.
어, 대부분 비손실 압축 알고리즘에 대한 일을 해요.
- A what? - It makes files smaller.
- 뭐요? - 파일을 작게 만드는 거요.
Doesn't matter. Uh, it's called Pied Piper.
아니 그게, 파이드 파이퍼라는 건데,
It's gonna be famous. You'll know it, eventually.
당신도 뭔지 알게 될 정도로 유명해질거예요.
Who was this woman that you shook hands with for the first time?
처음으로 악수한 여자는 누구였어?
The postman lady.
여자 우편 배달부(postman lady).
- What? - A woman that was a man?
- 뭐? - 성전환 수술 받은 여자?
Not a post-man lady.
남자였던(post-man) 여자가 아니고,
- A lady who was a post... - Let me ask you another question.
- 편지 배달해 주는... - 다른 질문이나 물어봐.
Who was the second woman you shook hands with?
두번째로 악수한 여자는 누구였어?
(BIG HEAD) I didn't even know you were coming.
(BIG HEAD) I didn't even know you were coming.
- (MOCHACINO) Stop. (YELLS) Doug! - Oh, boy.
- 꺼져. 더그! - 어, 이런.
- Stop. - I don't think I'm the one...
꺼지라고.
Someone is paying me. Ok. I didn't come
얼른 돈이나 줘. 공짜로 네 꼴린 물건 위에서 춤춰주러 온거 아니거든.
I was not erect. I... that was... I was only being polite.
선게 아니라, 그냥 공손하게 굴려고...
So you were being polite when you said that you loved me?
날 사랑한다고 말한 것도 그 공손하게 군거라고요?
First off, I said you seemed like someone I could fall in love with.
우선, 당신은 사랑에 빠질만한 여자라고 말한거고,
And, yes, also politeness.
그리고, 맞아요. 공손하게 건넨 말이었어요.
Richie, pay the lady.
리차드, 요금 좀 내줘.
What? Why... Why should I pay her?
엥? 왜... 왜 내가 돈을 내야 하는데요?
I didn't hire her. I didn't even get a lap dance.
내가 부른 것도 아니고, 나한테 랩댄스를 춰준 것도 아닌데요.
This is a company party and you're the CEO.
이건 회사 파티고, 네가 사장이잖아.
- So pony up. - No.
- 그러니까 얼른 줘. - 싫어요.
If anyone should pay her it should be you.
요금은 당신이 내줘야죠.
Doug, help the CEO find his money.
더그, 사장이 지갑 꺼내게 도와줘.
No. No, no. We don't... I don't need help.
아뇨. 아뇨, 아뇨. 그럴 것까진 없어요.
I know where it is. It's here.
돈 줄께요.
- (MOCHACINO) Mm-hmm. - It's all here.
- 거의 다 됐어요. - 으음..
Do you... I don't know... Do you accept amex?
저기... 그게... 신용카드도 받나요?
- You damn right I do. - Put a hundred on there for yourself, Mocha.
- 물론 카드도 되죠. - 모카, 거기에 100달러 더 얹어서 긁어.
- Well, that's an expensive boner. - Not a boner.
- 꼴린 값 비싸네... - 꼴린 건 아니라니까.
- (SIGHS) - Thanks for coming in, guys.
와줘서 고맙네.
We have a lot to do, so,
저희가 좀 바쁘니까,
let's get started.
바로 시작하도록 하죠.
Sounds great.
알겠습니다.
Me? Ok.
제 순서 였나요?
Uhh...
어...
Well, we're just really excited to get going, Mr. Gregory.
그게... 그레고리씨, 저희는 이번 일을 매우 기대하고 있습니다.
Yes. Who's "we"?
그렇군. "저희"라는게 누구를 말하는 거지?
Myself, him, uh,
저랑, 이 사람, 그리고...
- the guys back at the house. - Guys?
- 집에 있는 친구들이요. - 친구들?
What guys?
어떤 친구들?
Who is this?
그리고 이 사람은 누구지?
Erlich Bachman. I'm an entrepreneur,
얼릭 바크만. 당신이랑 비슷하게
much like yourself. Uh...
사업가고요. 음...
Richard actually developed Pied Piper
리차드는 제 인큐베이터에 있는 동안
while residing in my Incubator,
파이드 파이퍼를 개발했습니다.
so as per our agreement, I own ten percent of the company.
인큐베이팅 계약에 따라서 제가 이 회사의 지분 10%를 갖게 되죠..
I'm paying you $200,000 for five percent
난 5%의 지분을 갖는 조건으로 2억원을 투자하기로 했는데,
yet you're giving this man...
당신은 그 두배를 받아가면서 이부자리랑 샌드위치 따위를 제공한다고?
Actually, sir, my tenants provide their own food...
대표님, 사실, 제 인큐베이터 입주자들은 음식은 알아서 해결합니다.
What other percentages have you apportioned?
또 지분 나눠주기로 약속된 것 있나?
(SIGHS) Can I see your cap table, investment deck,
회사 지분표랑 투자 유치 자료 좀 볼 수 있을까?
business plan or any other relevant paperwork
사업계획서나 뭐 다른 자료라도 말야.
you may have prepared?
준비는 해 왔지?
I... I just was under the impression that, uh...
어... 제가 상상했던 건,
we would just be coming by and saying "hi", you know,
저희가 그냥 와서 인사드리면,
uh, to pick up the check.
그냥 돈을 주는 건 줄 알았는데요.
And, uh, I just didn't know that any of that stuff was due yet.
거기에 숙제가 있는 줄은 몰랐어요.
- "Due"? - (SIGHS)
"숙제"?
This is not college, Richard.
리차드, 여긴 대학이 아닐세.
I am not going to be giving you a course syllabus.
수업계획서 같은 건 내가 주는게 아니야.
You turned down ten million dollars
자네는 파이드 파이퍼를 계속 소유하겠다고 100억원을 포기했어.
What did you give up that money for? What is this company?
뭘 위해서 그런 거금을 포기한거지? 이 회사는 뭘 하는 회사고?
What did I buy?
내가 뭘 사야하는 거지?
- You bought the algorithm, which... - No.
- 그 알고리즘에 돈을 내시는 걸로... - 아니네.
The algorithm is the product of the company.
알고리즘은 자네 회사의 상품이야.
I know that.
내가 알기로는 말야 .
What I'm asking about is the company itself.
내가 묻는 것은 상품이 아니라 회사 자체라네.
Who is it? What do they do?
이들은 누구인지? 이들이 누구인지?
Are they essential?
전부 필수 인력인가?
Or do you just throw a percentage at them like you did with this...
아니면, 지분을 막 나눠주는건 아닌가?
This all must be worked out.
이런 것을 전부 해결해야 하네.
Now.
지금 바로
When you said you'd guide us
저희를 도와준다고 했을 때,
through some of the stuff I thought that this was
그런 일들을 도와주시는 건 줄 알았는데요.
I cannot guide you until you give me...
자네가 나한테 뭘 도와줘야하는지,
something to guide.
자료를 주지 않으면 내가 뭘 도와줄 수 있겠나?
This is going very poorly.
이거 좋지 않게 진행되는 군.
(WHISPERS) I know that.
그렇네요.
He doesn't seem to know what he's doing.
자기가 뭘 해야하는지도 모르고 있어.
Did you just take a sip from an empty cup?
빈 컵을 들고 들이키고 있는건가?
Yes.
옙.
Why did you do that?
왜 그런 행동을 하는거지?
- Just something to do. - Come back in 48 hours
- 뻘쭘해서요. - 48시간 내로 다시 오게.
with an airtight business plan,
제대로된 사업계획서를 챙겨서 말야.
a clear go-to-market strategy
명확한 상용화 전략과
and three year summary P&I or there will be no check.
3년치 손익 요약표를 갖고 오지 않으면 돈은 없는 거야.
That's it.
오늘은 여기서 접지.
(MONICA) Well, thanks for coming in, guys.
음, 와주셔서 고마워요.
Um... are there any water fountains in your offices?
음... 사무실에 식수대가 있나요?
I assume.
있겠지?
I own ten percent of an app that locates all nearby water fountains.
주변의 식수대를 찾아주는 앱의 지분 10%를 소유하고 있는데,
I'd be happy to discuss it with you.
거기에도 투자하실 생각이 있으면 흔쾌히 응하겠습니다.
Good day, gentlemen.
잘가게나.
You smoke weed?
대마초 피워요?
You really embarrassed me in there.
너 때문에 진짜 쪽팔렸다.
You didn't say shit about any business plan before today.
여태까지 사업계획서 같은 이야기 꺼낸 적도 없잖아요.
And neither did he. And he was kind of being an asshole back there.
그레고리도 그래요. 엄청 재수 없게 구네요.
Yeah, that's why he's a billionaire. 'Cause he knows how and when to be an asshole.
그래, 저 사람은 자기가 언제 재수없게 굴어야하는지 아니까 부자인 거야.
That's what you need to be like.
너도 저 사람처럼 되어야 하고.
- You do, Richard. - Whatever.
- 알겠어, 리차드?. - 글쎄요.
If you continue to mismanage this company giving ten percent to whoever...
회사 지분 10% 씩 누군가한테 주는 식으로 회사를 잘못 운영하면...
Obviously, you know, we can't go back on my shares.
어... 뭐, 그렇다고 내 지분을 다시 가져갈 수는 없는 거고.
That ship has sailed but from here on out.
그 배는 떠난거고, 앞으로 말야.
Now you're being an asshole.
지금 당신이 재수없게 굴고 있네요.
You say that like it's a bad thing.
너 그게 나쁜 것처럼 말하네?
Richard, if you're not an asshole, it creates this kind of
리차드, 네가 싸가지 없게 굴지 않으면, 거기엔 싸가지가 부족해져서
asshole vacuum and that void is filled by other assholes, like Jared.
재러드 같은 다른 싸가지들이 그 자리를 채우게 될거야.
I mean, you almost gave him shares.
그러니까, 재러드한테 지분을 줄 뻔했잖아.
You need to completely change who you are, Richard.
리차드, 넌 완전히 다른 사람이 되어야해.
A complete teutonic shift has to happen.
Teutonic 변동이 생겨야 한다고.
Tectonic.
지각.
What?
뭐?
A "tectonic" shift is the earth's crust moving around.
지각 변동이 지구의 지각이 움직이는 것을 말하는 거고,
"Teutonic", which is what you just said,
방금 말한 teutonic 변동은
is an ancient Germanic tribe that fought the Romans.
is an ancient Germanic tribe that fought the Romans.
They were originally from Scandinavia...
They were originally from Scandinavia...
Stop it! Stop it.
그만, 그만!
You're being a complete tool right now.
넌 지금 그냥 공대 남자 잖아.
I need you to be a complete asshole.
그런 것 말고 싸가지 없는 사람이 되야 한다고.
Do you understand the difference?
뭐가 다른지 알지?
If you're not an asshole, this company dies.
네가 싸가지 없는 놈이 되지 않으면 회사는 망하는 거야.
Erlich, I have 48 hours.
얼릭, 48시간 남았어요.
Are you going to help me with this business plan or not?
비즈니스 계획 짜는 것 도와줄꺼예요, 말꺼예요?
I believe in you, Richard. That's why I'm not.
리차드, 난 네가 알아서 할 수 있다고 믿어.
"Business plans that are created in support of new ventures
"새 벤쳐 회사의 사업 계획은 기존 벤처 회사와의 차이점을 명확하게 강조해야 한다."
Uh...
음...
Hi, this is Richard Hendricks.
여보세요.
Is now a good time?
지금 통화 가능하냐고요?
Uh, I need some help.
어..., 마침 도움이 필요하던 참이예요.
Who's Chevy Volt is that out front?
앞에 셰비 볼트 세워져 있던데 누구 차야?
Uh, Jared Dunn's.
어, 재라드 던이 왔어요.
What? Why? Why is he here?
뭐? 왜? 그 자식이 왜 여기 있는데?
Well, because as you know, I need some advice on the business plan.
음... 알다시피 사업계획서 쓰는데 도움이 좀 필요해서요.
- You're cutting him in? - Um...
- 걔를 껴주겠단 말야? - 음...
Good morning. Whoops, that was weird.
좋은 아침. 어라? 좀 어색하네요.
I don't know why I did that.
제가 왜 그랬었는지 모르겠어요.
You kind of have a... Like a king-ish feeling to you.
왕 같이 위엄있어 보이네요.
You're like a... Like a Norse hero from Valhalla.
북부 유럽 신화에 나오는 영웅 같아요.
Don't pander to me.
나한테 아부 떨지마.
Peter Gregory said specifically to trim the fat.
피터 그레고리가 '군살'을 빼라고 말했잖아.
They actually tried to diagnose me with a wasting disease because of my slender frame.
제가 군살이 너무 없어서 소모성 질환 진단 받을 뻔 했죠.
So, um, I ironed out our customer acquisition strategy,
그래서, 음 고객 유치 전략을 바로 잡아 봤어.
and I wrapped our financials, I did a DCF valuation.
거기에 재정 상황이랑 현금 흐름 평가서도 작성했고.
Most VC's can't even do that math, but something tells me Peter is different.
대부분의 벤처 투자자는 그런 계산도 잘 못하지만, 왠지 피터 그레고리는 좀 다를 것 같아서.
I think we can jump into the one-on-ones with each team member
각 팀원들이랑 1대1로 지분에 대해서 이야기 해볼 차례 같네.
Um, but first, if you don't mind, I'd like to use the restroom.
음, 그전에 화장실 좀 다녀올께.
Yeah. You don't have to ask permission to do that.
그런 것까지 허락 받을 필요는 없어.
Why, have you not gone since you've been here?
여기와서 한번도 안갔던 거야?
I have not.
안 갔어.
Well... well, go. I mean, go.
음... 그게, 가. 가라는게 나가라는 게 아니고 화장실 말하는 거야.
Denpok, I know you were in Aspen, thank you for coming. Please, have a seat.
덴폭, 아스펜에 계시는 줄 알았는데, 와줘서 고마워요. 어서 앉으세요.
I'm not sitting this summer.
이번 여름에는 앉이 않기로 했다네.
Of course. Incredible.
그렇군요. 굉장하네요.
What's weighing on you, Gavin?
뭐 때문에 마음이 무거운거지?
Jared Dunn quit today to join Pied Piper.
오늘 재러드 던이 사표내고 파이드 파이퍼로 가버렸어요.
I hate Richard Hendricks, that little Pied Piper prick.
그 쬐끄만한 파이드 파이퍼의 사장 새끼가 미워 죽겠어요.
Is... is that wrong?
그게 잘못된 건가요?
In the hands of a lesser person, perhaps.
보통 사람들은 그렇게 생각하겠죠.
But in the hands of the enlightened, hate can be a tool for great change.
그렇지만 깨우친 사람에겐 증오는 변화의 계기가 되어주기도 합니다.
You're right once again.
또 옳은 말씀 해주시는 군요.
Audious, play John Lennon's "Imagine."
아디오스, 존 레논의 'Imagine" 재생.
(BEEPING)
재생 목록 추가, 존 웨인의 "In a Mansion". 찾을 수가 없습니다.
- Fuck! Fuck! - (AUDIOUS) Invalid command.
- 씹팔! 씹팔! - (AUDIOUS) 유효한 명령이 아닙니다..
Use the anger, chela. Use it.
분노를 사용하도록 하게.
Uh, thanks for sitting down like this, Gilfoyle.
자리해줘서 고마워, 길포일.
We know it's kind of a little weird.
이 자리 좀 어색하긴 하지만...
So, um... can you kind of catch me up on what you see as your role in the company?
음... 회사에서 네 역활이 어떻다고 생각해?
What do you do?
무슨 일을 하고?
What do I do?
내가 무슨 일을 하냐고?
System architecture. Networking and security.
시스템 설계. 네트워크와 보안.
No one in this house can touch me on that.
여기 누구도 그걸로는 나랑 비교가 안되지.
Ok, that's good to know.
오케이. 그거 좋네.
But does anyone appreciate that?
But does anyone appreciate that?
While you were busy minoring in gender studies
네가 새라 로렌스 대학에서 부전공으로 여성학 공부하거나
and singing a capella at Sarah Lawrence,
아카펠라 부르면서 시간 보내는 동안
I was gaining root access to NSA servers.
난 안보국 서버의 관리자 권한을 확보하고 있었어.
I was one click away from starting a second Iranian revolution.
클릭 한 번만 하면 2번째 이란 혁명을 일으킬 수 있을 정도 였다고.
I actually went to Vassar.
난 바사 대학 출신인데,
I prevent cross-site scripting, I monitor for DDoS attacks,
크로스 사이크 스크립트를 차단하고, DDoS 공격을 감시하거나
emergency database rollbacks, and faulty transaction handlings.
긴근 데이터베이스 복구나, 잘못된 트랜잭션을 다루거나 할 수 있어.
The Internet... heard of it?
인터넷이라는 건데... 들어는 봤지?
Transfers half a petabyte of data every minute.
매분마다 500 기가 바이트의 데이타가 전송된다고.
Do you have any idea how that happens?
그게 어떻게 가능한지 알 수나 있겠어?
All those YouPorn ones and zeroes streaming directly
매일 YouPorn(포르노사이트)의 동영상들이 0, 1로 바뀌어서
to your shitty, little smart phone day after day?
네 엿같은 폰으로 스트리밍 되는 방법을 알겠냐고.
Every dipshit who shits his pants if he can't get
덥스텝 스크릴렉스의 새 리믹스 다운 받는데 12초 넘게 걸린다고
the new dubstep Skrillex remix in under 12 seconds?
바지에 똥이나 지리는 놈들도 있다고.
It's not magic, it's talent and sweat. People like me, ensuring your packets
그건 마법이 아냐. 재능과 땀으로 일군 기술이라고.
get delivered, un-sniffed. So what do I do?
get delivered, un-sniffed. 그래서 내가 뭘 할 수 있냐고?
I make sure that one bad config on one key component
중요한 컴포넌트 하나가 잘못되어서 회사를 통채로 말아먹는 일이
doesn't bankrupt the entire fucking company.
생기지 않도록 막아줄 수 있어.
That's what the fuck I do.
내가 그런 좃나 멋진 능력자란 말야.
That's basically what I told him.
내가 얘한테 비슷하게 말해두긴 했어.
Listen, wherever we end up here...
잘들어. 여기서 나눈 이야기가 어떻게 결론이 나든,
I just wanna say that I feel
내가 꼭 하고 싶은 말이 있는데,
I should get more equity than Dinesh.
난 디네시보다는 많이 받아야겠어.
I know Gilfoyle probably came in here and puked out a bunch of tech specs,
길포일이 여기서 자기 능력 자랑을 잔뜩 하고 갔을텐데,
three-fourths of which are total horse-shit.
그 중에서 3/4는 완전 헛소리야.
Did he bring up the Iranian revolution thing?
걔가 또 이란 혁명 이야기 꺼냈지?
Yeah, those words mean nothing.
아무 의미 없는 헛소리야.
But here's a fact: I'm the only one of these clowns that can code in Java.
진실을 이야기하자면, 여기 광대들 중에서 자바로 코딩할 수 있는 건 나뿐이야.
And I write sleek performant low-overhead scala code
그리고 오버해드 거의 없이 깔끔하게 성능 뽑아주는 스칼라 코드도 짤 수 있고.
with higher order functions that will run on anything.
아무데서나 가져다 쓸 수 있는 고차 함수도 포함해서 말야.
Period. End of sentence. So basically, I think whatever equity I get,
마침표. 설명 끝. 그러니까 내가 얼마를 받게되든지.
it should reflect that I contribute more than Gilfoyle.
길포일보다는 내 공이 더 크다는 걸 명심해줘.
- This is weird. - (CHUCKLES) I know, right? It's...
- 이거 좀 그러네. - 그러게 말야...
- Everybody's been doing it. - Gilfoyle did this?
- 그래도 다들 하고 있어. - 길포일도 했어?
It's just a formality, to get me caught up.
그냥 형식적으로 하는거야. 내가 상황 좀 파악해야 되서.
So what makes you of value to the Pied Piper team?
그래서 넌 파이드 파이퍼에게 어떤 가치를 제공할 수 있어?
Um... programming.
음... 프로그래밍.
I guess... pretty good at code, develop algorithms... So forth.
코딩 실력이나 알고리즘 개발 능력이 꽤 괜찮은 편이야.
Different from the type of algorithm Richard created?
리차드가 개발한 알고리즘이랑은 다른 거야?
Well, yeah. Like, not as good.
뭐 그렇지, 비슷해. 그만큼 좋지는 않지만.
Richard's a 10x-er, I'm, like, barely an x-er.
리차드가 만든 건 10배쯤 된다고 하면, 난 그냥 평범해.
- (BOTH CHUCKLING) - I kinda suck.
- (BOTH CHUCKLING) - 내 실력은 좀 구려...
Smoked you. And now...
Smoked you. And now...
- Don't be a dick. - Mushroom stamp!
- 좃같이 굴지 좀 마. - 버섯 도장 확보!
- You're being a dick. - There you go. Show that to your mom.
- 이 좃같은 새끼. - 좋네, 네 엄마한테도 보여주자.
Mushroom stamp! That's great.
버섯 도장! 그거 멋지네.
Hey, what do you guys think about this Jared? He's shit, right?
이봐, 재러드 어떻게 생각해? 걔 완전 별로인거 맞지?
No, he's pretty sharp.
아뇨, 꽤 날카로운 시각을 갖고 있던데요.
Yeah, he does shit that no one else in the house can do.
맞아, 여기있는 사람 아무도 못하는 짓거리를 잘 해내다라고.
Yeah, but he's a know it all. I don't think there's room in here for him.
그래도 아는 척이 심하잖아. 걔한테 나눠줄 건 없을 것 같은데 말야.
Well, there will be after Richard gets rid of Big Head.
뭐, 왕 대갈이 짤리면 나눠줄게 생기겠죠.
Wait, Richard's getting rid of Big Head? Why?
뭐? 리차드가 왕 대갈이를 짜를 거라고?
Listen, we all love Big Head.
그게, 우리 전부 왕대갈이 좋아하긴 하지만
But, the truth is he's not as good of a coder as I am,
사실 걔가 나처럼 코드를 잘 짜는 건 아니죠.
not as good at system architecture as Gilfoyle,
길포일처럼 시스템 설계를 잘하는 것도 아니고,
not as good at being a prick as you, no offense.
당신처럼 병신력이 높은 것도 아니고 말예요. 아 나쁜 뜻은 아녜요.
He's a lightweight at everything. Brings nothing to the table.
왕 대갈이는 모든 분야에서 어쩡쩡해요. 거래할 꺼리가 없죠.
Him getting points would be a big "fuck you" to all of us.
걔가 점수를 따는 건 우리 모두한테 엄청난 모욕이라고요.
- But he's a great guy. - Great guy. But useless.
- 하지만, 걔는 참 좋은 애라고. - 좋은 애지만, 쓸모는 없죠.
Yeah, he is a great guy. Not like that Jared.
그래, 참 좋은 애야. 재러드랑은 다르지.
(SCOFFS) At least we can all agree on that.
이건 전부 공감하는 거잖아.
Yeah, I don't know.
그게, 모르겠네.
Me and Richard have just always been in this together, you know?
나랑 리차드는 항상 같이 있었어.
Together, right. But to be clear, Richard created the algorithm on his own, yes?
항상 말야. 하지만 분명히하자면, 알고리즘은 리차드가 혼자 만든거지.
Oh, yeah, I had nothing to do with that.
난 거기에 아무것도 해준게 없어.
- He's my best friend. - That's true.
- 내 베프야.. - 맞아.
Yes. The camaraderie is quite apparent.
그래. 둘의 우정은 잘 알겠어.
But Peter Gregory demanded a lean, ruthless business plan.
하지만 피터 그레고리는 린하고 가차없는 사업계획을 요구했잖아.
And I don't think that the CEO of Microsoft has a paid best friend.
내가 알기로는 마이크로 소프트에 사장이랑 친하다고 돈 받는 사람은 없었을 거고.
- Sergey Brin does. (CHUCKLES) Larry doesn't do shit. - See?
- 세르게이 브린에겐 있지. 래리 페이지는 아무 것도 안한다고. - 봤지?
What if Big Head is sort of like
만약에 왕 대갈이를
a floating utility player? Like a jack of all trades.
다양한 분야를 보충해주면? Like a jack of all trades.
But by his own admission, he's really more like a master of none.
하지만, 본인의 평가로도 능숙하달건 딱히 없는데.
That's true. That is true.
그건 그렇지.
Which is not something you'd generally reward with several points in what may some day be
언젠간 몇백억짜리 회사가 될지도 모를 회사에서
a multi-billion dollar company.
지분을 나눠줄 정도로 대단하진 않은 것 같은데.
This will never fly with Peter Gregory.
피터 그레고리한테는 절대 안 먹힐 인사라고.
I would not want to be Richard right now.
지금 리차드 상황이 참 난감하겠다.
Having to tell Big Head that he's out.
베프인 왕 대갈이한테 나가라고 해야하다니.
This is gonna sound super mean, but the other night he was sleeping,
안 좋게 들리겠지만,
I was just staring at his face.
걔가 자고 있는 얼굴을 보면서 드는 생각이라고는,
All I could think was, "He's utterly useless."
'진짜 쓸모 없겠다' 뿐이었어.
Big Head is a man with zero purpose.
왕 대갈이는 아무 용도가 없는 애야
- Oh, hi. Hi, Big Head. - Hey.
- 왕 대갈, 이야기는 다 끝났어? - 예.
How's it going?
그래서 좀 어때?
It's... super good... Right now.
그게... 엄청 괜찮아요... 지금은
Um, I'm just going to maybe go for a bike ride real fast
아주 잠깐만 자전거 좀 타고 올께요.
and clear my... head.
잠깐 바람 좀 쐬고 싶어서요.
I'll see... you.
이따 보자.
- Bike safe. - Yeah, enjoy it.
- 조심해서 타. - 그래 잘 타고 와.
That was nice, guys. He heard everything.
잘하는 짓거리다. 다 들었다고.
That doesn't make it not true.
틀린 말 한건 아니잖아.
I mean, come on, Richard. As far as Pied Piper is concerned,
리차드, 파이프 파이퍼 관련 일에서 걔는
he's as pointless as Mass Effect 3's multiple endings.
매스 이펙트 3의 여러 엔딩처럼 아무 의미 없는 애라고.
I mean, he's a completely useless appendage and we all know it.
내 말은, 걔가 아무짝에 쓸모없는 부록이라는 걸 다들 알고 있잖아.
- Oh, hey, man. - Forgot my water bottle.
- 어 벌서 왔네.. - 물병을 두고 가서..
Just gonna grab it, and then probably walk right back through one more time.
물병 집어서, 한번 더 지나가야 할 것 같아.
I mean, Mass Effect 3? Harsh.
매스 이펙트 3? 좀 심했어.
I didn't mean for him to hear it but it was true.
본인 들으라고 한 이야기는 아닌데, 틀린 말은 아니잖아요.
I mean, we all called him a great guy but he didn't overhear any of that.
좋은 애라고 말해준건 듣지도 못했는데 말야.
It's been 12 hours.
12시간이 지났는데,
Goddamn. He's still not answering.
제길, 아직도 전화 안 받아.
(STAMMERING) I'm actually kind of worried about him.
나 이제 좀 걱정되기 시작했어.
You know, if he's gone, like, really truly gone,
만약에 걔가 진짜로 돌아가신거면,
in a way that kind of solves your problem.
네 걱정거리가 하나 사라지는 거기도 해.
I mean, like, if he's dead...
그러니까 걔가 죽은거면 말야.
Are you trying to say that Big Head might be dead?
어떻게 사람이 죽는다는 이야기를 그렇게 할 수 있어?
That doesn't help at all. How is that helping?
그런 말은 전혀 도움이 안되. 그게 어떻게 내 걱정을 해소해 준다는거야?
I'm just saying that that's a possible thing that could've happened to him.
내가 하고 싶은 말은, 그런 일은 누구한테나 생길 수 있는 거고
It could happen to anybody. And in this case, at least something good came out of it.
왕대갈이 그런 일 당했다면, 좋은 점이 하나 있다는 거야.
What's the good part?
좋은 점이 대체 뭔데?
You don't have to have an awkward conversation.
하기 힘든 말을 안해도 되잖아.
That's scary. Should we go look for him?
오히려 무서운데, 참으러 가봐야겠죠?
I mean, I agree with these guys. Jared's just not working out.
나도 얘네들이란 같은 심정이야. 재러드는 안된다고.
- What? - Um, Richard...
- 뭐라고요? - 음, 리차드?
I, uh, don't wanna be too assertive here
내가 이러기는 좀 그렇긴 한데,
but I could use your input on a few things for the business plan.
사업계획서 만드는데, 네가 좀 도와줄게 있어.
Richie, you tried your best just call him, leave a message, say he's out.
리치, 네가 할 일은 다 한거야. 그냥 전화나 문자로 빠지라고 해.
No, that's an asshole move.
싫어요. 그건 진짜 쓰레기 같은 짓이예요.
Yeah, remember? You need to be an asshole.
그래, 내가 한 말 기억나? 넌 싸가지 없는 놈이 되야해.
I feel bad about saying that thing about him being dead.
죽음 어쩌고 말한게 마음이 불편하네.
That's not who I am.
내가 원래 그러는 타입은 아닌데...
- Wait, what is that? - That's impossible.
- 잠깐, 그거 뭐야? - 말도 안되.
NipAlert isn't live yet.
NipAlert은 아직 배포된게 아닌데,
Maybe he's demoing it for someone.
누군가한테 데모해주나 봐요.
"Mochacino."
모카치노!
He rode his bike to San Jose?
자전거 타고, 새너 제이까지 간거야?
Jared, can I borrow your car?
재러드, 차 좀 빌려줄래?
- Sure. - I have a car.
- 그래. - 나도 차 있어.
What... What's wrong with my car?
내... 내차는 싫어?
I just have... I don't know.
그게... 글쎄요.
All right, well, remember to be an asshole.
좋아. 싸가지 없게 굴어야 한다는 거 잊지마.
A real asshole.
진짜 개 쓰레기가 되란말야.
Hi, I'm Richard Hendricks. You did a dance... The dancing at my house.
안녕하세요. 전 리차드 헨드릭스라고 하는데, 전에... 저희 집에 춤추러 온 적 있죠?
Your ride's here.
너 데리러 왔다.
Oh, hey, man.
어, 왔어?
- Hey. - Mushroom stamp!
- 응. - 버섯 도장!
No, come on, dude, not...
이런... 또 이러면...
I just wanted to work with computers and get paid for it.
난 그냥 컴퓨터로 일하면서 돈도 좀 벌고 싶었을 뿐이야.
I didn't want end up fighting with my roommates over percentage points.
룸메이트랑 회사 지분 같은 걸로 싸우고 싶었던게 아니라고.
So you're just gonna give up?
그래서 그냥 포기하려고?
On what? This isn't home.
그러면? 난 갈데도 전혀 없어.
As much as I've tried, it's just not.
나름 노력해봤지만, 어쩔 수 없더라고.
I mean, what would've I have even done if I didn't have Mochacino's card?
모카치노 명함이라고 없었으면 대체 뭘 했을까?
Where would I have gone? It's fucking pathetic.
대체 어디로 갔을까? 좃나 불쌍한 내 인생.
Well, Mochacino seemed to like you. She let you into her apartment.
모카치노는 널 맘에 들어하나 보던데, 뭐. 집에도 들여보내줬잖아.
I had to give her my bike. She's just like everyone else in this goddamn Valley.
들어가려고 자전거 줬어. 그녀도, 이 재수없는 마을 사람들이랑 똑같다고.
Watching the bottom line. Fuck it, dude. I'm done here.
밑바닥만 보고 사는 것 좃까라 그래. 난 여기 뜰꺼야.
What about NipAlert?
NipAlert은 어쩔려고?
Mochacino shows her tits for a living and even she was uncomfortable using it.
모카치노는 가슴 보여주는 걸로 먹고 사는데도, 그거 쓰기 싫다더라.
She said it was sexist. She's right. It's actually perverted.
성차별 적이라고 하더라고. 맞아. 이건 그냥 변태짓꺼리야.
I made a perverted, sexist, useless thing.
내가 만든 건 변태스럽고, 성차별적이면서, 쓸모도 없어.
And, you know, everybody's right, man,
너도 알겠지만 다른 애들이 한 말이 다 맞아.
there's nothing for me to do on Pied Piper.
파이드 파이퍼에서 내가 할 수 있는 건 아무것도 없어.
I think over time, maybe we could redefine your role.
글세, 시간이 지나면 네 역활도 찾게 될거야.
Come on, dude. Unless you can tell me right now what I can do for Pied Piper
리차드, 지금 바로 딴 사람은 못하지만
that no one else can, I'm gone.
나만 할 수 있는 일을 말해봐. 못하면 그냥 떠날거야.
I'm going to go get the stuff out of my cube at Hooli
훌리에 있는 내 짐이나 싸서,
and then I'm getting the hell out of this town.
바로 이 마을을 뜰거야.
So this is goodbye then?
그럼 이제 헤어지는 거야?
I mean, I'll see you back at the house, man. I gotta, like, pack and stuff.
짐도 싸고 해야하니까, 집에서 또 보게되긴 하겠지.
Totally.
물론 그렇지만...
I'm going to take the train I think, just... Do some thinking...
기차타고 가면서... 생각도 좀 해보고...
Ok, all right, see ya.
그래, 알겠어. 이따가 보자.
- The train is this way... I just... - Oh. I was gonna say.
- 기차는 이쪽이야. 그냥 그렇다고... - 나도 그 말하려고 했어.
Big Head...
왕 대갈.
Whatever shit you're about to dump on my head, you can save it, ok? I'm not in the mood.
나한테 무슨 개소리를 하려고 하는거면, 넣어둬. 지금은 그럴 기분 아냐.
Dude, I just wanted to tell you that Gavin Belson wants to talk to you about something.
이봐, 난 그냥 개빈이 너랑 할 말이 있데서, 알려주러 온거야.
- Oh, ok. Fuck you. - No. Seriously.
- 좃이나 까. - 아니, 진짜로.
Gavin Belson said he wants to speak to Nelson Bighetti?
개빈 벨슨이 넬슨 비게티랑 대화를 나누고 싶다고?
Yeah, that's what I just said.
그래, 그 말하러 온거야.
Come on.
얼른 와.
Ok.
이거...
I'm awake! I'm awake.
나 안자, 자는 거 아니야.
- What? - No, no, I wasn't.
- 뭐? - 아냐. 아무것도 아냐.
I was sleeping. I'm sorry for sleeping and for lying about it.
잠 들었었어. 잔거랑 거짓말 한 것둘 다 사과할께.
For both. No good.
둘 다. 옳지 않았어.
What happened? Did you fire Big Head?
어떻게 됐어? 왕 대갈이 해고했어?
Uh, no. Not yet. I don't know. Sort of.
그게, 아직 아냐. 사실 잘 모르겠어.
So do I include him in the cap table or not? It's basically good to go.
지분표에 포함시킬까, 뺄까? 거의 완성됐거든.
Uh... no, he's out. Uh, wait... I don't know.
음... 일단은 빼. 아니, 잠깐... 아직도 잘 모르겠어.
Actually, I just need to close my eyes for a little bit. Ok?
잠깐 눈 좀 붙이고 결정할께.
Richard, it's t-minus four hours until presentation time.
리차드, 4시간 밖에 안 남았어.
Are you gonna fire Big Head or not?
왕 대갈이 뺄거야, 말거야?
I don't know. Uh... I'm just very tired.
아직 모르겠어요. 지금 좀 피곤하네요.
Ok? I'm just gonna go get some water...
알겠죠? 우선 물 좀 마시고...
Richard, stop being a fucking pussy and start being an asshole.
리차드, 계집애처럼 굴지 말고 싸가지 없는 인종이 되야한다고.
Fine! You want me to be an asshole, I'll be an asshole.
좋아요. 내가 그러길 원하면, 그렇게 할 께요.
I'll be an asshole to you and you and you and you and Peter-fucking-Gregory!
당신이랑, 너랑, 너랑 너한테 나쁜 놈이 되고, 좃같은 피터 그레고리한테고 그렇게 한다고!
Ok? Fuck all of you. Big Head stays!
됐어? 다들 엿먹으라 그래. 왕 대갈이는 같이 갈꺼야!
You know, if I wanted to be a sell out I'd have done that already.
내가 그럴 사람이었으면 진작에 그랬을 거라고.
I'd be on a beach somewhere with ten million dollars in my pocket.
그랬으면, 지금쯤 어느 해변에 앉아서 100억이 든 지갑을 갖고 있었겠지.
Not in my pocket, in a bank account.
지갑이 아니라, 은행에 넣었겠네.
Ok? This is my company. It was my idea and we do what I say.
알겠어? 이건 내 회사야. 내 아이디어에서 시작했고, 내가 하고 싶은대로 할거라고.
And what I say is, Jared, put Big Head in the business plan.
그리고 재러드, 내가 하고 싶은 말은 왕 대갈이도 사업계획서에 넣어줘.
He gets the same amount of shares as everybody else.
왕 대갈이도, 다른 사람이랑 똑같이 받게 될거야.
Big Head, you're not going home, man.
왕 대갈, 너 집에 안 갔구나.
You're right. I'm not.
응, 나 안가.
Gavin Belson just offered me a huge promotion
개빈 벨슨이 너희들한테서 날 빼앗으려고
for 600 grand a year to steal me away from you guys.
승진시켜줘서 연봉으로 6억원 받게 됬거든.
- What? - Yeah. For revenge. Because you took Jared.
- 뭐? - 그래 네가 재러드 데려간거에 복수하려고 말야.
So you're like the V.P. of spite?
So you're like the V.P. of spite?
But you have to do me a favor, Richard,
근데, 부탁하나 할께.
if you run into Gavin ever you have to act really upset about it, you know?
개빈 벨슨 만나게 되면, 엄청 화난척 좀 해주야해. 알지?
Oh, but I am upset.
그런데, 나 화나 있는데.
Ok? What the fuck? I kind of just went out on a limb for you here, man.
이게 뭔 좃같은 경우야? 난 너 때문에 막 밀어 붙였는데,
Sorry, man, but this is huge for me.
미안해, 그런데, 이건 나한테 엄청난 기회라고.
I'm going to move out, get my own place.
여길 떠나서 내 자리를 잡을거야.
In light of this new information, who gets Big Head's equity?
이 상황에서 누가 왕 대갈이의 지분을 갖게 되는 거야?
Should I get half of his shares...?
내가 그 중 반정도 가져도 될까?
I do. I get it.
나야. 내가 갖을거야.
Ok? I get all of it!
알아? 내가 다 가질거라고.
Big Head, man, congratulations on the job, really.
왕대갈, 좋은 일 잡아서 축하해.
But if you'll excuse me, I have to go lock down a motherfucking business plan.
But if you'll excuse me, I have to go lock down a motherfucking business plan.
Jared, you're with me.
재러드, 같이 가자.
- What an asshole. - Yeah. What an asshole.
- 개자식. - 그러게, 개자식 다 됐네.
Next.
다음 분이요.
- Hi. Deposit? - Mmm-hmm.
안녕하세요. 입금하시게요?
Two hundred thousand dollars from Peter Gregory?
피터 그레고리에게 받은 2억짜리 수표요?
- Wow. - (PHONE RINGING)
우와.
Sorry.
잠시만요.
Hello?
여보세요?
Dude, they're taking your code apart.
쟤네들이 네 코드 뜯어보고 있어.
What?
뭐?
Did you give those brogrammer guys access to a player download or something?
형제 프로그래머한테 플레이어 다운 받게 해주거나 했어?
Oh shit. They probably hacked the prototype and decompiled the compression library...
젠장. 걔네들이 프로토타입 뜯어서, 압축 알고리즘을 디컴파일 하겠네.
Well, they've got it now, man.
걔네들 작업 들어갔어.
They're gonna reverse-engineer a version as close as they can without getting sued.
고소 당하지 않을 정도로만 최대한 비슷하게 리버스-엔지니어링한 버전을 만들겠지.
(RICHARD) Wait, wait, are you sure about this?
이거 확실한 거야?
(BIG HEAD) Yeah, dude, Gavin wants to beat you to market.
그래, 개빈은 너보다 먼저 출시하려고 하고 있어.
He wants to make sure no other investor in the Valley offers you a dime.
실리콘 밸리의 다른 투자자들 아무도 너한테 투자 안하게 말야.
(EXHALES) That is not good.
좋지 않은데...
They're calling it Nucleus, whatever the fuck that means.
뭔 뜻인지는 몰라도 "핵"이라고 부르더라.
Shit. Sorry, dude, I can't be talking to you like this. Later.
이런, 미안, 나 너한테 이런 말 하면 안되는 거라서. 나중에 이야기해.
Yeah.
그래.
"Nucleus"?
"핵"?
Excuse me. This check is made out to "Pied Piper Incorporated."
실례지만, 이 수표는 '파이드 페이퍼 기업'에게 발행되거예요.
Do you have an SS-4?
SS-4 갖고 계세요?
A what?
그게 뭔데요?
Is "Pied Piper" a corporation registered with the IRS?
파이드 파이퍼가 국세청에 등록된 회사인가요?
I can't deposit that into a personal account.
개인 개좌로 입금할 수는 없거든요.
(STAMMERING) I don't know.
글쎄요.
Um... is that something maybe you could help me with?
여기서 바로 어떻게 도와주실 수는 없나요?
No, sir.
죄송합니다.
Buddy, come on.
이봐요.
Uh-huh. Yeah, yeah.
어..어. 예
- Thank you. - Sorry. Ok.
- 고맙습니다.. - 죄송해요.
Next.
다음 분.